# Charles A. Beynon Full Stack Web Developer

With over five years of experience as a systems administrator, IT generalist, and computer instructor in K-8 education, I'm looking to move on to a more hands-on, full-stack developer role.

@eToThePilPower eToThePilPower in linkedin.com/in/cbeynon ☐ https://eulerpi.io charles.a.beynon@gmail.com

**1**-347-433-5690

I've been preparing over the last three years, including completion of a coding boot camp, self-study, and a number of personal projects. My primary back-end language is Ruby on Rails, with testing in RSpec/Capybara, and the frontend in HTML/HAML/SCSS. I am currently diving deep into AngularJS, and I'm always exposing myself to new technologies to keep a fresh mind and broader outlook.

Ideally, I'm looking for a team committed (as I am) to rigorous engineering practices but that also recognizes the human aspect; that software is written by, and for, people. I consider a heavy use of pair-programming, test-driven development, and continuous integration; a focus on communication between team members/clients; and a commitment to developer growth through mentorship and professional development; to be strong indicators of a team I'll be successful at.

#### Skills

## Languages

- Ruby / Ruby on Rails
- HTML / CSS / SCSS
- AngularJS / jQuery

#### Exposed to / Interested in

- Go
- Node, Meteor
- Scala
- · Octave, R

## **Technologies**

- Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS, Gentoo)
- PostgreSQL
- Mac OS Server (ACTC Certified)
- · Amazon AWS / Alexa Skills
- Google Apps (Domain Admin)

## Exposed to / Interested in

- · Continuous Integration
- Docker

# Selected Projects

## Connectly (Upcoming)

A contact management tool that keeps track of the people you meet, what you talked about recently, and gently reminds you to renew those connections and keep your promises. Rails 5 / Angular 2

#### Quotebook (2016-2017)

A tool to collect, organize, and share quotations from various sources, including directly entered and from Kindle Highlights. Rails 5

## Bootstrap4Jekyll (2017)

A theme for Octopress & Jekyll based on Bootstrap 4

- Integrated résumé page generation, with printer-friendly stylesheet
- Responsive, accessible, and open-source

## Octopress Image Caption Tag (2014)

A Ruby gem adding advanced, semantic image captioning support to Octopress and JekvII

## Reservester (2013)

An OpenTable clone, created as the final project at Startup Institute Rails 4 / ¡Query

# Experience

# Student, Web Development Track

Startup Institute New York New York, NY

June 2010-August 2013

Systems Administrator Laurel Hill School

East Setauket, NY

May 2010-May 2013

Startup Institute is the #1 career accelerator, helping individuals gain the skills, mindset, and network to succeed in jobs at startups.

- Developed an OpenTable clone using Ruby on Rails, JQuery, and Test Driven Development
- Partnered with Mortar Data to redesign their website using responsive web design.

Maintained and administered all technology on campus for ~50 staff and ~400 students, and teaching summer workshops for older students in Web Development, Digital Animation, and Video Game Design.

- · Built remote deployment system using DeployStudio and NetInstall for Mac OS X
- Migrated and administered email and calendar services to Google Apps

## Education

B.S. Mathematics / Physics

SUNY Binghamton September 2007-May 2010